Guide to the New Deal in Montana/Fort Peck Dam Oral History Project 1987-1989
Montana Historical Society Research Center
- THOMAS BULL-OVER-HILL INTERVIEW, OH 1164; 1 tape(s), Transcript 9 pages
  Thomas Bull-Over-Hill discusses his recollections of superintendents Asbury and Yellowtail; the appointment of district boss farmers on Crow Agency; first celebration of Sundance on Crow Agency in 1941; Crow Fair celebrations; his experiences in the Crow Fair Rodeo; rodeo participants Carl Leider, George Shaver, Jimmy Cooper, Joe Littlebird, and Anos High Eagle; building Round Halls; peyote use and conflicts with police; his work in CCC and WPA programs; and herding buffalo on the Montana-Wyoming border. Interviewed by Carson Walks Over Ice, May 27, 1987, Crow Agency, Mont.
- JOHN BULLTAIL INTERVIEW, OH 1165; 1 tape(s), Transcript 14 pages
  John Bulltail, a Crow Tribe elder, discusses the introduction of the Sundance to the Crow Agency Reservation, Montana; origins of the Crow Fair celebrations; Fourth of July celebrations in Lodge Grass; the Self Determination Act; CCC projects; and the BIA (Bureau of Indian Affairs) cabin near Indian Creek. Interviewed by Carson Walks Over Ice, June 13, 1989, Hardin, MT.
- GEORGE TAKES THE GUN INTERVIEW, OH 1166; 1 tape(s), Transcript 17 pages
  George Takes The Gun (1909-1993) discusses his recollections of Crow Agency School Superintendents' Asberry and Yellowtail; the Boss Farmer program; the history of Crow Fair; Crow Fair celebrations; the Sundance; caring for Buffalo herd in the 1940s; going to school in Lodge Grass, Montana; building Round Halls; WPA programs; peyote; and his experiences building roads. Interviewed by Carson Walks Over Ice, June 8, 1989, Hardin, MT.
- GERARD PESMAN INTERVIEW, OH 1167; 3 tape(s), Transcript 57 pages
  Gerard Pesman (1906-2000) discusses his father's work for the Huntley and Hysham, Montana irrigation projects which began in 1909; his own work driving tour buses in Yellowstone National Park from 1926 to 1941; the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC); his childhood. Interviewed by John Terreo, June 19, 1989, Bozeman, MT.
- RAY J. QUIST INTERVIEW, OH 1168; 1 tape(s), Summary 13 pages
  Ray Quist (b. 1916) discusses his childhood in Forsyth, Montana; family's relocation to Bozeman in 1925; experiences as a mechanic and tour bus driver in Yellowstone National Park from 1935 to 1939; World War II service as an aircraft mechanic of B-17 bombers; work in the farm machinery and equipment business. Interviewed by John Terreo, June 19, 1989, Bozeman, MT.
- BUD POSTEMA INTERVIEW, OH 1169; 2 tape(s), Transcript 56 pages
  Bud Postema (1911-1998) discusses his parents and homesteading in the Manhattan, Montana area; early life and education; his family's grocery business; the 1930s Depression; Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC); Yellowstone Park Transportation Company; experiences and recollections as a tour bus driver; park visitors, other drivers and various other employees; and retirement. Interviewed by John Terreo, June 20, 1989, Bozeman, MT.
- DONALD STEELE INTERVIEW, OH 1170; 2 tape(s), Summary 21 pages
  Donald Steele (b. 1912) discusses his childhood in Billings, Montana; his father's work as chief of the Billings Fire Department; and his experiences as a tour bus driver in Yellowstone National Park from 1935 to 1941. Interviewed by John Terreo, June 22, 1989, Billings, MT.
- EUGENE A. DUNLOP INTERVIEW, OH 1202; 2 tape(s), Summary 4 pages
  Eugene Dunlop discusses his work as a mechanic and dispatcher for the Yellowstone National Park Transportation Company; and bus models used in the park. Interviewed by John Terreo, June 26, 1989, Helena, MT.